{"tossups": [{"question": "A ruler of this dynasty whose lineage was questioned took out his sword, shouted \"here is my pedigree!,\" and threw gold coins into a crowd; that ruler of this dynasty commissioned scientists to invent the world's first fountain pen. This dynasty's capital was founded by a Dalmatian Christian named Jawhar (jow-har). A ruler of this dynasty angered Basil the Bulgar Slayer by ordering the destruction of the Church of the Holy Sepulcher; that possibly insane ruler of this dynasty had his reputation enhanced by the preacher Shaykh Darazi (\"shake\" dah-RAH-zee), causing him to become worshipped by the Druze faith. This dynasty built al-Azhar (al ah-ZHAR) University and was ruled by the \"Mad Caliph\" (KAY-lif) al-Hakim. The Ayyubid (\"EYE\"-oo-bid) dynasty followed, for 10 points, what Cairo-based dynasty named for one of Muhammad's daughters?", "answer": "Fatimid dynasty [or Fatimid Caliphate; or al-Fatimiyun; accept Fatamids]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Fatimid</u></b> dynasty [or <b><u>Fatimid Caliphate</u></b>; or <b><u>al-Fatimiyun</u></b>; accept <b><u>Fatamids</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Fatimid dynasty", "Fatimid", "Fatimid Caliphate", "al-Fatimiyun", "Fatamids"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to the Annals of the Cakchiquels (\"cock\"-chee-kells), the culture hero Gagavitz entered one of these locations named Gagxanul (gahg-shah-nool) while Zakitzunun (zah-KEET-zoo-noon) poured water mixed with grass and corn into it. In Guanche (GWAN-chay) myth, the primary malevolent deity, Guayota (gwah-YOH-tah), lives in one of these locations. In a Nahua (NA-hwa) story, two of these locations are formed when a princess, whose name means \"white lady,\" kills herself after hearing a lie about how her lover died in battle. A goddess who lives in one of these locations used her power over them to destroy the white mantle of her rival, the snow goddess Poliahu (poh-lee-ah-hu). Two of these locations near Mexico City are said to be the lovers Iztacci\u0301huatl (iz-tahk-see-hwa-tul) and Popocatepetl (poh-poh-cah-TEH-\"petal\"). Pele lives in the crater of Kilauea, which is an example of, for 10 points, what type of  ery mountain?", "answer": "volcanos [accept calderas or volcanic craters before \"crater\"; prompt on \"mountains\" before \"mountain\"]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>volcanos</u></b> [accept <b><u>calderas</u></b> or <b><u>volcanic craters</u></b> before \"crater; prompt on <u>mountains\"</u> before \"mountain]", "acceptable": ["volcanos", "volcanos", "calderas", "volcanic craters"], "promptable": ["mountains\""], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The mannerist portico of this man's house provides the backdrop for a painting, titled The Garden of Love, that he made to celebrate his wedding. His wife modeled for a painting of a mostly nude woman cradling her breasts in her arm and wrapping a pelt across her shoulder and around her hips, which this man titled The Fur. Around 20 years earlier, he painted himself near a flowering bush, holding his first wife's hand, in The Honeysuckle Bower. A0er Isabella Brant died of plague, this man married a woman nearly 40 years his junior named Helena Fourment (foor-MAWN). He included The Presentation of the Portrait and The Disembarkation at Marseilles (mar-SAY) in a series commissioned by the Queen Mother of France. For 10 points, what Flemish artist of the Marie de' Medici cycle painted many fleshy nudes?", "answer": "Peter Paul Rubens [or Paul Peter Rubens]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Peter Paul Rubens</u></b> [or <b><u>Paul Peter Rubens</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Peter Paul Rubens", "Peter Paul Rubens", "Paul Peter Rubens"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A Wulff (VULF) plot predicts the results of this technique, which, in molecular biology, is done using vapor diffusion in a hanging drop apparatus. Industrially, this technique is done in tanks containing draft tubes and baffles; in lab, it is done in a Craig tube. The trade-off between chemical potential and surface energy in this process yields embryos of a critical nucleus in size. The Czochralski (cho-KRAHL-ski) process is a form of this technique done to silicon. Chiral resolution using this technique adds a chiral compound like tartrate to form a dia\u00b7stereo\u00b7mer. The remnant of this technique is called the mother liquor. In this process, a seed serves as a nucleation site when a dissolved ionic salt crashes out above its solubility limit. For 10 points, name this purification technique that forms ordered products, unlike precipitation.", "answer": "crystallization [or word forms; or recrystallization; or crystal growth; or forming crystals; or obvious equivalents; prompt on precipitation or word forms; prompt on nucleation or word forms; prompt on puri cation or separation]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>crystallization</u></b> [or word forms; or <b><u>recrystallization</u></b>; or <b><u>crystal growth</u></b>; or <b><u>forming crystals</u></b>; or <b><u>obvious equivalents</u></b>; prompt on <u>precipitation</u> or word forms; prompt on <u>nucleation</u> or word forms; prompt on <u>puri cation</u> or <u>separation</u>]", "acceptable": ["crystallization", "crystallization", "recrystallization", "crystal growth", "forming crystals", "obvious equivalents"], "promptable": ["precipitation", "nucleation", "puri cation", "separation"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the aftermath of this event, measures were taken to suppress the illegal practice of \"puncturing\" and to require the increased use of stone from Gabii or Alba. According to Tacitus, this event took place on the anniversary of a Gallic raid following the Battle of the Allia. Titus Flavius Sabinus, who was praefectus urbi (\"pry\"-FEKT-oos OOR-bee) during this event, put the City Guard to work so that the Vigiles (wee-jee-lays) could  nd time to sleep. Celer (CHEH-lur) and Severus oversaw the construction of the Domus Aurea after this event, for which Christians were scapegoated. The emperor, who was away at Antium, was nevertheless popularly blamed for this event, during which he allegedly played the lyre and sang about the fall of Troy. For 10 points, what disaster destroyed much of the capital during the reign of Nero?", "answer": "Great Fire of Rome [accept answers referring to the Roman  re of 64 CE or the Roman  re during the reign of Nero; prompt on partial answers]", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Great Fire of Rome</u></b> [accept <b><u>answers referring to the Roman  re of 64 CE</u></b> or the <b><u>Roman  re during the reign of Nero</u></b>; prompt on <u>partial answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["Great Fire of Rome", "Great Fire of Rome", "answers referring to the Roman  re of 64 CE", "Roman  re during the reign of Nero"], "promptable": ["partial answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A0er seeing terrifying visions, such as an \"orcus-pregnant space bursting with grotesque animal-life,\" this character resolves to destroy all he has created in a chapter titled \"Fire\u00c2\u2014The Descent.\" He regrets pursuing art over the love of Plotia (PLOH-tee-ah) in that novel, which begins with his arrival at Brundisium (broon-DEE-see-um) accompanied by his patron. This man discourses on the nature of Fortune to explain the futility in addressing groups of spendthri0s and hoarders locked in perpetual combat in a poem in which he summons Geryon so that he and his companion can reach Malebolge (MAH-leh-bol-jeh). Hermann Broch wrote about the \"death\" of this character, who approaches a man lost in a dark wood \"midway through life's journey\" at the start of an epic poem. For 10 points, what Roman poet guides Dante through the Inferno?", "answer": "Virgil [or Publius Vergilius Maro; accept The Death of Virgil or Der Tod des Vergil]", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Virgil</u></b> [or <b><u>Publius Vergilius Maro</u></b>; accept <b><u>The Death of Virgil</u></b> or <b><u>Der Tod des Vergil</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Virgil", "Virgil", "Publius Vergilius Maro", "The Death of Virgil", "Der Tod des Vergil"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An experimental paradigm in which these entities are presented, unmoving, to infants was devised by Edward Tronick and colleagues. Novel objects that share constraints with these entities and that were developed by Isabel Gauthier are known as \"greebles.\" Nancy Kanwisher proposed that an area in the brain's fusiform gyrus is speci cally dedicated to processing information about these entities. The Thatcher effect is the dif culty of perceiving anomalies in these entities when viewed upside down. An example of pareidolia (\"pair-eye\"-doh-lee-ah) is an image from Viking 1 of the Cydonia region of Mars that appears to show one of these entities. Prosopagnosia (pro-so-pag-NO-zee-ah) is an impairment in the visual processing of, for 10 points, what part of the body that people typically look at to \"recognize\" other people?", "answer": "human faces [accept facial recognition or perception; prompt on \"human heads\" or similar answers]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>human faces</u></b> [accept <b><u>facial recognition</u></b> or <b><u>perception</u></b>; prompt on <u>human heads</u> or <u>similar answers</u>]", "acceptable": ["human faces", "human faces", "facial recognition", "perception"], "promptable": ["human heads", "similar answers"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This author created a character who asks to be read the Fouque\u0301 story \"Aslauga's Knight,\" comes to think of Bess as his Aslauga, and redeems himself after a murder by saving miners from drowning. In a novel by this author, a man tells his love that he has nothing to offer but his empty hands, upon which she places her hands in his and says \"not empty now.\" This author wrote about Dan, Demi, Nan, and Nat, who attend an experimental school with scheduled pillow  ghts that is called Plum eld and is run by Professor Bhaer and his wife. In another novel, this author wrote about Beth, who dies after contracting scarlet fever, leaving behind her sisters, Meg, Jo, and Amy. For 10 points, name this author of Jo's Boys and Little Men, the sequels to her popular novel Little Women.", "answer": "Louisa May Alcott", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Louisa May <b><u>Alcott</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Louisa May Alcott", "Alcott"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A wooden lyre discovered inside a royal tomb in Ur features a gold bull's head that has a beard of this color. The body of an animal  gurine from the Middle Kingdom is glazed with a light shade of this color and decorated with black outlines of river plants; that sculpture, commonly called \"William the Hippo,\" exempli es Egyptian faience (\"fie\"-AHNTS), which was most frequently glazed this color. A structure that is predominantly this color features rows of gold bas-relief aurochs, representing the storm god Adad, and mushussus (moo-SHOO-sooz) which are sacred to Marduk. The Pergamon Museum in Berlin houses a structure built from bricks glazed over with this color that once served as an entryway in Babylon. For 10 points, name this color of the Ishtar Gate, which was covered in lapis lazuli.", "answer": "blue [accept any particular shade of blue such as ultramarine; accept turquoise or teal or blue-green]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>blue</u></b> [accept <b><u>any particular shade of blue such as ultramarine</u></b>; accept <b><u>turquoise</u></b> or <b><u>teal</u></b> or <b><u>blue-green</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["blue", "blue", "any particular shade of blue such as ultramarine", "turquoise", "teal", "blue-green"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Alexander II was convinced to back the Union cause by a politician from this state who served as Abraham Lincoln's ambassador to Russia; that \"Lion from White Hall\" defended the office of his newspaper, the True American, from a pro-slavery mob in this state with his trademark Bowie knife. Jeroboam O. Beauchamp murdered Solomon P. Sharp during a legal crisis in this state that occurred during the Panic of 1819. The politician Cassius M. Clay was from this state, which was the site of the Old Court\u2013New Court controversy. A politician from this state proposed extending the Missouri Compromise boundary through the west in a namesake 1860 \"compromise\" intended to solve the sectional crisis. For 10 points, what state's politicians included John Crittenden and the \"Great Compromiser,\" Henry Clay?", "answer": "Kentucky [or Commonwealth of Kentucky]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Kentucky</u></b> [or <b><u>Commonwealth of Kentucky</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Kentucky", "Kentucky", "Commonwealth of Kentucky"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In QFT, the n-point Green's functions, or correlation functions, are de ned by this quantity for a time-ordered product of  elds, which itself is related to the scattering amplitude by the LSZ reduction formula. The time derivative of this quantity for a time-independent operator is \"i over h-bar\" times this quantity for the operator's commutator with the Hamiltonian, a more general case of Ehrenfest's theorem. This value equals the trace of the density matrix, rho, times an operator. It can be de ned as the bra of a state times an operator times the ket of a state, or as the integral over all space of the product of the conjugate wavefunction, an operator, and the wavefunction. This value for an operator squared minus the square of this value for an operator is a de nition of uncertainty. For 10 points, what quantity is the mean value of an observable in quantum mechanics?", "answer": "vacuum expectation value [or VEV; or expected value; or condensate; accept mean value before \"mean\"; prompt on average value]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>vacuum expectation value</u></b> [or <b><u>VEV</u></b>; or <b><u>expected value</u></b>; or <b><u>condensate</u></b>; accept <b><u>mean value</u></b> before \"mean; prompt on <u>average value</u>]", "acceptable": ["vacuum expectation value", "vacuum expectation value", "VEV", "expected value", "condensate", "mean value"], "promptable": ["average value"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Otto, Duke of Carinthia, owned a forti ed house in this city that served as a haven for criminals until a bishop's campaign to have the house destroyed; that bishop of this city compiled a 20-volume legal text called the Decretum and was named Burchard. An agreement named for this city used the terms \"by the lance\" and \"by the ring and staff\" to distinguish between the secular and sacred authorities of appointed bishops. In this city, a religious reformer stated that his \"conscience is captive to the Word of God.\" Callixtus II and Emperor Henry V ended the investiture controversy by signing a concordat in this city, where a man under the protection of Frederick the Wise declared \"here I stand, I can do no other.\" For 10 points, what city hosted the Imperial Diet where Martin Luther was named a heretic?", "answer": "Worms (VURMS) [accept Burchard of Worms or Concordat of Worms or Diet of Worms]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Worms</u></b> [accept <b><u>Burchard of Worms</u></b> or <b><u>Concordat of Worms</u></b> or <b><u>Diet of Worms</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Worms", "Worms", "Burchard of Worms", "Concordat of Worms", "Diet of Worms"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "VURMS"}, {"question": "In performances of the Moderato e maestoso last movement of this composer's Second Symphony, it has become tradition for the trumpet to hold a high B for an extra bar. This composer wrote a major-key symphony whose D-minor Lento last movement establishes the piece's cyclic form by ending with the nobilmente (noh-beel-MEN-tay) theme of the  rst movement. This composer used the unusual key of A-&amp;at major for his First Symphony. In the Intermezzo: Allegretto tenth section of a piece by this composer, the woodwinds parody a woman's stutter. This composer wrote a piece in D whose trio section, \"Land of Hope and Glory,\" is traditionally played on the last night of the Proms. For 10 points, name this English composer of the Enigma Variations and the Pomp and Circumstance Marches.", "answer": "Edward Elgar [or Sir Edward William Elgar, 1st Baronet]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Edward <b><u>Elgar</u></b> [or <b><u>Sir Edward William Elgar, 1st Baronet</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Edward Elgar", "Elgar", "Sir Edward William Elgar, 1st Baronet"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This play includes the prophecy that the \"mother of disasters\" will occur \"where the plain grows lush and green\" because a man has been insolent and scorned god. A messenger in this play relays a battle cry that includes the call to \"set free your children, wives, places of your ancestral gods, and tombs of your ancestors\" after listing the names of generals killed in battle. Near the beginning of this play, a woman recounts a dream in which her son attempts to put a bridle and yoke on two women. In one scene in this play, a former king appears before Atossa and rebukes his son for using ships to form a bridge to allow troops to cross a channel. For 10 points, name this tragedy by Aeschylus in which the ghost of Darius is summoned in the aftermath of Xerxes's defeat at Salamis.", "answer": "The Persians [or Persai; or Persae]", "subcategory": "Classical Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Persians</u></b> [or <b><u>Persai</u></b>; or <b><u>Persae</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Persians", "Persians", "Persai", "Persae"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a 1998 book proposing a \"theory\" of this phenomenon, Bernard Baars proposed a computational architecture for it called the \"global workspace theory.\" A 1995 paper on \"facing up\" to the study of this phenomenon claims that the discussion of it is subject to an \"explanatory gap.\" An argument against the existence of the \"Cartesian theater\" appears in a book that offers a \"multiple dra0s\" model of this phenomenon. A Daniel Dennett book attempts to \"explain\" this phenomenon, which is central to the writings of David Chalmers and is not possessed by \"philosophical zombies.\" The role of qualia is central to the \"hard problem\" of, for 10 points, what mental phenomenon that can be de ned as the subjective awareness of one's own existence?", "answer": "consciousness [accept word forms such as conscious; accept \"Facing Up to the Problem of Consciousness\" or Consciousness Explained]", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>consciousness</u></b> [accept <b><u>word forms such as conscious</u></b>; accept <b><u>Facing Up to the Problem of Consciousness</u></b> or <b><u>Consciousness Explained</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["consciousness", "consciousness", "word forms such as conscious", "Facing Up to the Problem of Consciousness", "Consciousness Explained"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "When this substance is treated as a dilute suspension, its effective viscosity can be de ned as liquid viscosity scaled by the quantity \"1\" minus \"1.35 times the fraction of bubbles and crystals,\" all raised to the \"minus 2.5 power,\" which is called the Einstein\u00c2\u2013Roscoe equation. This substance is formed when its precursors follow an adiabat from the geotherm and cross the wet or dry solidus. This substance's composition is changed by assimilation of fusibles in crustal rocks. As this substance's temperature drops, fractional crystallization of ma c minerals makes it more felsic, corresponding to Bowen's reaction series. It's usually classi ed as basaltic, andesitic, or rhyolitic. For 10 points, what substance is molten rock found beneath Earth's surface, where it collects in namesake chambers?", "answer": "magma [do not accept or prompt on \"lava\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>magma</u></b> [do not accept or prompt on \"lava\"]", "acceptable": ["magma", "magma"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": ["lava"], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In this country, the mayor of the town of Albuera, Rolando Espinosa, was killed in a possibly staged gun ght in November 2016. This country's president has accused opposition senator Leila de Lima of facilitating a clandestine shabu ring based in New Bilibid prison. In 2016, the leader of this country said \"she was so beautiful; I thought, the mayor should have been  rst,\" implying that he wanted to sleep with a nun named Jacqueline Hamill, who was raped and killed in a 1989 hostage crisis. This country's president called Barack Obama a \"son of a whore\" in defending extrajudicial killings that have occurred during a harsh anti-drug campaign similar to the one its president conducted while mayor of Davao (dah-\"VOW\") City. For 10 points, name this country led by Rodrigo Duterte from Manila.", "answer": "The Philippines [or Republic of the Philippines; or Republika ng Pilipinas]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "The <b><u>Philippines</u></b> [or <b><u>Republic of the Philippines</u></b>; or <b><u>Republika ng Pilipinas</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["The Philippines", "Philippines", "Republic of the Philippines", "Republika ng Pilipinas"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the lab, this structure is synthesized using an enzyme puri ed from vaccinia (vak-SIN-ee-ah) virus with supplemented S-adenosyl methionine (ess ah-DEN-oh-sill meh-\"THIGH\"-oh-neen). Flu virus \"snatches\" this structure. Eukaryotic initiation factor 3 binds this structure, which is analogous to a bacterial I\u00c2\u00b7R\u00c2\u00b7E\u00c2\u00b7S. Synthesis of this structure is activated when its namesake enzyme binds phos\u00c2\u00b7phoryl\u00c2\u00b7ated hepta\u00c2\u00b7peptide repeats on Pol II (\"paul two\") right after initiation. This structure, which is located upstream of the Kozak sequence and A\u00c2\u00b7U\u00c2\u00b7G, is oddly attached to the rest of the U\u00c2\u00b7T\u00c2\u00b7R by three phosphates. This structure, a single 7-methyl\u00c2\u00b7guanosine nucleotide, protects against exo\u00c2\u00b7nucleases and is added during transcription before introns are spliced out. For 10 points, name this sequence that is located opposite the poly(A) (\"poly-ay\") tail and is added to the 5-prime end of mRNAs.", "answer": "5-prime cap [or 7-methylguanosine cap; accept answers mentioning caps instead of \"cap\"; prompt on \"messenger RNA\" or \"messenger ribonucleic acid\"]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "5-prime <b><u>cap</u></b> [or <b><u>7-methylguanosine cap</u></b>; accept <b><u>answers mentioning caps instead of \"cap</u></b>; prompt on <u>messenger RNA</u> or <u>messenger ribonucleic acid</u>]", "acceptable": ["5-prime cap", "cap", "7-methylguanosine cap", "answers mentioning caps instead of \"cap"], "promptable": ["messenger RNA", "messenger ribonucleic acid"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This poet wrote that, although \"a prince can make a belted knight, / a marquis, [or a] duke,\" \"the pith of sense and pride of worth / are higher rank than all that.\" He noted that \"my Mary's asleep by thy murmuring stream\" in a poem that asks the title river to \"&amp;ow gently\" so as to \"disturb not her dream.\" This poet of \"A0on Water\" wrote a poem in which the speaker pledges to love until \"the rocks melt with the sun\" and \"while the sands of life shall run.\" Another of his poems is addressed to a creature that \"art blessed, compared with me\" because \"the present only toucheth thee.\" In that poem about a \"wee, sleeket, cowran, tim'rous beastie,\" this man wrote that \"the best laid schemes o' Mice an' Men gang a0 agley\" (gahng ah  ah-GLAY). For 10 points, name this Scottish poet of \"A Red, Red Rose\" and \"To a Mouse.\"", "answer": "Robert Burns [or Rabbie Burns; prompt on \"Bard of Ayrshire\" or \"Ploughman Poet\"]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Robert <b><u>Burns</u></b> [or <b><u>Rabbie Burns</u></b>; prompt on <u>Bard of Ayrshire</u> or <u>Ploughman Poet</u>]", "acceptable": ["Robert Burns", "Burns", "Rabbie Burns"], "promptable": ["Bard of Ayrshire", "Ploughman Poet"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This man bathed alone, convincing people he had a scrotal hernia or a skin problem until a stone ran off with his clothes and he had to chase after it naked. He met a servant of God who astonished him by  rst damaging a ship and then killing a young boy before revealing that those seemingly evil acts were actually righteous. When this man was given a choice between a plate of rubies and a plate of burning coals, he took a coal and stuck it in his mouth. In Islamic tradition, this man's life is considered to parallel the life of Muhammad. This son of Amram convinced Muhammad to reduce the number of obligatory daily prayers from 50 to  ve. For 10 points, name this most frequently mentioned individual in the Quran, a prophet who received the Ten Commandments.", "answer": "Musa ibn Amram [or Moses]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Musa ibn Amram</u></b> [or <b><u>Moses</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Musa ibn Amram", "Musa ibn Amram", "Moses"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In the context of D-branes, this force is described by closed strings that move in the bulk. The gauge theory of this force is diffeomorphism (di\u00c3\u00be-ee-oh-\"morphism\") invariant. The Weinberg\u00c2\u2013Witten theorem states that this force's gauge boson cannot be composite. A major problem in theoretical physics arises from the fact that, at two-loop level, theories of this force are not perturbatively renormalizable. The A\u00c2\u00b7d\u00c2\u00b7S/C\u00c2\u00b7F\u00c2\u00b7T correspondence involving this force relates the  eld of a massless spin-two gauge boson in AdS to the stress-energy tensor in CFT. A linearized theory of this force uses perturbation around Minkowski spacetime to  nd solutions to the Einstein  eld equations. For 10 points, quantum theories of what attractive force are generated by quantizing general relativity?", "answer": "gravity [or loop quantum gravity; or linearized gravity; or gravitational force]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>gravity</u></b> [or <b><u>loop quantum gravity</u></b>; or <b><u>linearized gravity</u></b>; or <b><u>gravitational force</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["gravity", "gravity", "loop quantum gravity", "linearized gravity", "gravitational force"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}